A Guide to the Papers of Albert Erskine, 1930-1999
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series II: James A. Michener
  - James A. Michener- Iberia Correspondence, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 14:7)
    This folder includes his plan for the book (April 29. 1966; and July 27, 1966); and a copy of the Book-of-the-Month Club report about Iberia written by Gilbert Highet and related material (December 19, 1967 and attached).
  - James A. Michener- Iberia Correspondence, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 14:8)
    Discusses British publication (February 2, 1968 and attached); reader reaction to the book (August 1, 1968); and an explanation as to why the book was initially banned in Spain (April 26, 1969).
  - James A. Michener- Iberia, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 14:9)
    Correspondence concerning photographs by Robert Vavra.
  - James A. Michener- Iberia, 1968, Dust Jackets. (Box-folder 14:10)
  - James A. Michener- Iberia, 1967 (Box-folder 14:11)
    Outline, Design and Production Materials.
  - James A. Michener- Iberia, 1968, n.d. (Box-folder 14:12)
    Outline, Design and Production.
  - James A. Michener- Iberia, 1967-1969, Reprint Corrections. (Box-folder 15:1)
  - James A. Michener- Iberia, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 15:2)
    Serialization.
  - James A. Michener- The Inheritors, 1987 (Box-folder 15:3)
    Includes an essay on Why the Book Was Written and some portions of typescript.
  - James A. Michener- Interviews, and Articles and Talks about Michener, 1964-1981, n.d. (Box-folder 15:4)
  - James A. Michener- Kent State: What Happened and Why, 1971, Book Production, Editorial Fact Sheet, "Foreword" and "Afterword," and Dust Jacket. (Box-folder 15:5)
  - James A. Michener- Kent State: What Happened and Why, 1972 (Box-folder 15:6)
    Campus Criticism and Michener's Rebuttal.
  - James A. Michener- Kent State: What Happened and Why, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 15:7)
    Correspondence, including Book-of-the-Month Club and Reader's Digest.
  - James A. Michener- Kent State: What Happened and Why, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 15:8)
    Editorial Changes and Corrections and Libel Review.
  - James A. Michener- Kent State: What Happened and Why, 1970-1971, n.d., News clippings and Reviews. (Box-folder 15:9)
  - James A. Michener- Kent State: What Happened and Why, 1971 (Box-folder 15:10)
    Photographs and Captions.
  - James A. Michener- Kent State Campus Under Fire,1971 April (Box-folder 15:11)
    The Reader's Digest Reprint.
  - James A. Michener- A Michener Miscellany: 1950-1970, 1970-1972 June (Box-folder 15:12)
  - James A. Michener- A Michener Miscellany: 1950-1970, 1972 August-1973 (Box-folder 16:1)
  - James A. Michener- Poland, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 16:2)
  - James A. Michener- Presidential Lottery, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 16:3)
    Book Production and Miscellany.
  - James A. Michener- Presidential Lottery, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 16:4)
    Correspondence concerning changes and corrections.
  - James A. Michener- Presidential Lottery, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 16:5)
    Permissions and Reviews.
  - James A. Michener- The Quality of Life, 1970, Typescript Copy with Memo from Bennett Cerf about the manuscript. (Box-folder 16:6)
  - James A. Michener and A. Grove Day- Rascals in Paradise, 1956 April-August (Box-folder 16:7)
    Correspondence and Corrections.
  - James A. Michener and A. Grove Day- Rascals in Paradise, 1956 September-1959, 1966 (Box-folder 16:8)
  - James A. Michener and A. Grove Day- Rascals in Paradise, 1956 (Box-folder 16:9)
    Leeteg, the Legend and Louis Becke, Adventurer and Writer Chapters- Typed Manuscripts.
  - James A. Michener- Report of the County Chairman, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 16:10)
  - James A. Michener- Return to Paradise, 1949-1970 (Box-folder 17:1)
  - James A. Michener- Russian Novel Material, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 17:2)
    Novel abandoned following his heart attack.
  - James A. Michener- Sayonara,1952-1969 (Box-folder 17:3)
    Includes a letter from a man claiming copyrights to the word "sayonara" and Michener's rebuttal (November 6, 1953).
  - James A. Michener- The Source, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 17:4)
    Cartography and Artwork Material.
  - James A. Michener- The Source Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 17:5)
    This file includes an outline of the book (June 7, 1963); his progress with the novel and attendance at a seminar of American Jewish writers and critics held jointly with writers and critics from Israel (June 26, 1963); questions over which version of the Bible to quote in his novel (July 10, 1963 and attachments); concerns of Meyer Levin that Michener's book might compete with his own book in progress (August 21, 1963 and attached; August 25, 1963); completion of 15 of the 17 sections (December 5, 1963 and attached); and his request to add the manuscript to the insurance of Random House at his expense until the entire thing is safely delivered in the mail (April 9, 1964).
  - James A. Michener- The Source Correspondence, including corrections, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 17:6)
    This folder includes the Book-of-the-Month Club report about The Source with Michener's note on its background (May 1965) and a group of corrections for the reprints in a separate insert, 1965-1967.
  - James A. Michener- The Source Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 17:7)
    Concerns British publication.
  - James A. Michener- The Source, 1965 (Box-folder 17:8)
    Flap Copy, Editing Notes, Advertising, and Photographs.
  - James A. Michener- The Source, 1965-1968 (Box-folder 17:9)
    Paperback Sale Figures and Fawcett Publications, Inc. - Correspondence.
  - James A. Michener- The Source Reviews and Reader Reactions, 1964-1967 (Box-folder 17:10)
    Includes controversy with Rabbi Ephraim Oshry.
  - James A. Michener- The Source, [1965?] (Box-folder 17:11)
    Typed Manuscript Copy (1 of 6 folders).
  - James A. Michener- The Source, [1965?] (Box-folder 17:12)
    Typed Manuscript Copy (2 of 6 folders).
  - James A. Michener- The Source, [1965?], Typed Manuscript Copy (3 of 6 folders). (Box-folder 18:1)
  - James A. Michener- The Source, [1965?] (Box-folder 18:2)
    Typed Manuscript Copy (4 of 6 folders).
  - James A. Michener- The Source, [1965?] (Box-folder 18:3)
    Typed Manuscript Copy (5 of 6 folders).
  - James A. Michener- The Source, [1965?] (Box-folder 18:4)
    Typed Manuscript Copy (6 of 6 folders).
  - James A. Michener- Space, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 18:5)
  - James A. Michener- Spanish Institute Gold Medal Award Dinner, 1980 (Box-folder 18:6)
  - James A. Michener- Sports in America Book Production, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 18:7)
    Includes editorial fact sheet, flap copy, and cartoon artwork.
  - James A. Michener- Sports in America Correspondence, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 18:8)
    Includes critique of manuscript (November 24, 1975), libel concerns, and Fawcett paperback edition.
  - James A. Michener- Sports in America, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 18:9)
    Permissions, Changes, and Corrections.
  - James A. Michener- Texas, 1983-1986 (Box-folder 19:1)
    Correspondence, Editorial Notes, Flap Copy, and Dust Jacket.
  - James A. Michener- Texas, 1984 (Box-folder 19:2)
    Fact and Fiction Synopsis and Editing Notes for Chapters 1-5.
  - James A. Michener- Texas, 1984 (Box-folder 19:3)
    Editing Notes for Chapters 6-8.
  - James A. Michener- Texas, 1985 (Box-folder 19:4)
    Editing Notes for Chapters 9-14.
  - James A. Michener- Texas, 1985 May 2, Edited Pages Proofs for the Front Matter and Chapters 1-2. (Box-folder 19:5)
  - James A. Michener- Texas, 1985 May 2, Edited Page Proofs of Chapters 3-4. (Box-folder 19:6)
  - James A. Michener- Texas, 1985 May 2-3, Edited Page Proofs of Chapters 5-6. (Box-folder 19:7)
  - James A. Michener- Texas, 1985 May 3, Edited Page Proofs of Chapters 7-8. (Box-folder 20:1)
  - James A. Michener- Texas, 1985 May 16, Edited Page Proofs of Chapters 9-10. (Box-folder 20:2)
  - James A. Michener- Texas, 1985 May 20, Edited Page Proofs of Chapters 11-12. (Box-folder 20:3)
  - James A. Michener- Texas, 1985 May 20, Edited Page Proofs of Chapter 13. (Box-folder 20:4)
  - James A. Michener- Texas, 1985 May 20, Edited Page Proofs of Chapter 14. (Box-folder 20:5)
  - James A. Michener- Texas, 1985 June, Maps with corrections and editing notes. (Box-folder 20:6)
  - James A. Michener- Texas, 1985 (Box-folder 20:7)
  - James A. Michener- Voice of Asia, 1951, 1959-1966 (Box-folder 20:8)
  - James A. Michener- The Watermen, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 20:9)
- Series III: Miscellaneous Authors
  - Richard Bankowsky (1928-), 1960-1963 July (Box-folder 21:1)
    The file includes editorial comments, reader's reports, author's explanation, and correspondence about his novels After Pentecost and On a Dark Night.
  - Richard Bankowsky (1928- ) Correspondence, 1963 September-1970 (Box-folder 21:2)
    Editorial material, dust jackets, and reviews concerning On A Dark Night; correspondence concerning Barbarians at the Gate (rejected by Random House), and his article "The Troilus as Thesis"(attached to September 20, 1963).
  - Lester Brown- World Without Borders, 1972 (Box-folder 21:3)
    Correspondence and Editorial Material.
  - Lester Brown- World Without Borders, 1968-1973 (Box-folder 21:4)
    Articles by Brown.
  - Lester Brown- World Without Borders, 1972 (Box-folder 21:5)
  - Matthew J. Bruccoli (editor with Margaret Duggan)- The Correspondence of F. Scott Fitzgerald, 1975-1979 (Box-folder 21:6)
  - Matthew J. Bruccoli (editor with Margaret Duggan)- The Correspondence of F. Scott Fitzgerald, 1980-1981, n.d. (Box-folder 21:7)
  - Matthew J. Bruccoli- John O'Hara Miscellany, 1972-1982 (Box-folder 21:8)
  - Matthew J. Bruccoli- The O'Hara Concern: A Biography of John O'Hara, 1970-1977, n.d. (Box-folder 21:9)
    Includes correspondence, flap copy and other editorial material, and reviews and comments about the book.
  - Matthew J. Bruccoli- Scott and Ernest, 1977 February-August (Box-folder 21:10)
  - Matthew J. Bruccoli- Scott and Ernest, 1977 September-December (Box-folder 21:11)
  - Matthew J. Bruccoli- Scott and Ernest, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 22:1)
  - Matthew J. Bruccoli (editor)- Selected Letters of John O'Hara, 1973-1977 (Box-folder 22:2)
  - Matthew J. Bruccoli (editor)- Selected Letters of John O'Hara, 1978-1979, n.d. (Box-folder 22:3)
  - Matthew J. Bruccoli (editor)- Selected Letters of John O'Hara, 1973-1978 (Box-folder 22:4)
    Contract Negotiations.
  - Bennett Cerf- At Random The Reminiscences of Bennett Cerf, ca. 1924-1967, n.d. (Box-folder 22:5)
    (Prepared for publication after Cerf's death by his wife, Phyllis Cerf Wagner and Albert Erskine )- Background and Financial Statements concerning Random House and the Modern Library (copies).
  - Bennett Cerf- At Random The Reminiscences of Bennett Cerf, 1933, 1951-1971 (Box-folder 22:6)
    (Prepared for publication after Cerf's death by his wife, Phyllis Cerf Wagner and Albert Erskine )- Biographical Information and Correspondence, including his obituary for Horace Liveright (October 7, 1933).
  - Bennett Cerf- At Random The Reminiscences of Bennett Cerf, ca. 1971-1976 (Box-folder 22:7)
    (Prepared for publication after Cerf's death by his wife, Phyllis Cerf Wagner and Albert Erskine )- Correspondence, editorial notes, outline of the book, draft of the editors' note about how the book came into being, and index to the book.
  - Bennett Cerf- At Random The Reminiscences of Bennett Cerf, 1977-1984 (Box-folder 22:8)
    (Prepared for publication after Cerf's death by his wife, Phyllis Cerf Wagner and Albert Erskine )- Correspondence, editorial notes, additional outlines of the book and drafts of the editors' note about how the book came into being, dust jacket, book excerpt, and a photograph of the Cerf family.
  - Bennett Cerf- At Random The Reminiscences of Bennett Cerf, 1977-1978, n.d. (Box-folder 22:9)
    (Prepared for publication after Cerf's death by his wife, Phyllis Cerf Wagner and Albert Erskine)- Reviews.
  - Bennett Cerf- Memorial Service for Cerf recorded by C. Weston, 1971 August 31, Reel-to-reel tape recording. (Othertype Audiotape 0242)
  - Sidney F. Davis- Point of Honor,1990 (Box-folder 23:1)
    Correspondence and Typed Manuscript (Copy), an unsolicited manuscript refused by Random House.
  - Sidney F. Davis- Point of Honor,1990, Typed Manuscript (Copy), an unsolicited manuscript refused by Random House. (Box-folder 23:2)
  - Theodore Dreiser- Photographs by Lotte Jacobi, n.d. (Box-folder 23:3)
  - Ralph W. Ellison- Articles, Reviews, and Essays by him, [1944?]-1986 (Box-folder 23:4)
  - Ralph W. Ellison- Articles concerning Ellison, 1973-1996, n.d. (Box-folder 23:5)
  - Ralph W. Ellison- Bibliography, 1968 (Box-folder 23:6)
  - Ralph W. Ellison- Correspondence, 1947-1959 (Box-folder 23:7)
    Includes letters responding to the pre-publication copy of The Invisible Man from Bernie Wolfe (May 10, 1951); Langston Hughes (January 15, February 6 and Mar 13, 1952); William Carlos Williams (March 22, 30 and April 4, 1952); Max Berking (April 5, 1952); Anton Myrer (April 5, 1952); Carl Van Vechten (March 19, 1952); Stanley Hyman (April 7, 1952); Granville Hicks (April 7, 1952); Peter F. Drucker (April 9, 1952); Frances McFa[dden ?] (April 12, 1952); Saul Bellows (April 12, 1952); Dr. Karl Menninger (April 22, 1952); Donat O'Donnell (April 28, 1952); Paul Bixler (April 29, 1952); and Jean [Stafford] (n.d.). All 1952 lettes are filed together in a yellow insert folder under January 15, 1952.
  - Ralph W. Ellison- Correspondence, 1960-1965 April (Box-folder 23:8)
    Includes various proposals from persons seeking screen rights to The Invisible Man; a tentative table of contents for Shadow and Act (November 12, 1963); and his letter supporting Erskine's nomination to The Century Club (April 26, 1965)
  - Ralph W. Ellison- Correspondence, 1965 May-1967 (Box-folder 23:9)
  - Ralph W. Ellison- Correspondence, 1968-1974 (Box-folder 23:10)
  - Ralph W. Ellison- Correspondence, 1979-1992, n.d. (Box-folder 24:1)
    Includes letters from Fanny Ellison to Marissa Erskine about several home improvements (January 15 and July 6, 1979); contract for Ellison's new book of essays (November 10, 1983); and a copy of his draft letter to Erskine Caldwell, discussing his reaction to the play version of Tobacco Road which he saw in New York in 1936 (September 16, 1983)
  - Ralph W. Ellison, 1963-1986, n.d., Dust Jackets and Photographs. (Box-folder 24:2)
  - Ralph W. Ellison- Flying Home and Other Stories, 1996, Advance Uncorrected Proof. (Box-folder 24:3)
  - Ralph W. Ellison- Interviews, 1964-1988, n.d. (Box-folder 24:4)
  - Ralph W. Ellison- The Invisible Man, [1952], n.d., Editorial Notes. (Box-folder 24:5)
  - Ralph W. Ellison- Juneteenth, 1996-1999 (Box-folder 24:6)
  - Ralph W. Ellison- Reviews of The Invisible Man, Shadow and Act, Going to the Territory and The Collected Essays of Ralph Ellison, 1947-1996 (Box-folder 24:7)
  - Ralph W. Ellison- Short Stories (Print Copies), 1944, n.d. (Box-folder 24:8)
    Includes Flying Home, In a Strange Country, King of the Bingo Game, and Mr. Toussaint.
  - Ralph W. Ellison- Speeches, Lectures, etc., 1953-1988 (Box-folder 24:9)
    Speeches, Lectures, etc., including the National Book Award Speech; Ralph Ellison: Selections from 'My Life and Yours'; What These Children Are Like; Remembering Richard Wright; On Initiation Rites and Power: Ralph Ellison Speaks at West Point; and Bearden.
  - Richard A. Falk- This Endangered Planet- Correspondence, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 24:10)
    Correspondence, including Senators Clifford P. Case, Thomas F. Eagleton, George McGovern, John V. Tunney, Stewart L. Udall, and Harrison A. Williams, Jr.; also includes United Nations Secretary-General U. Thant.
  - Richard A. Falk- This Endangered Planet, 1969-1971, n.d. (Box-folder 24:11)
    Editorial Notes, Reviews and Book Production Material.
  - David Felix- Correspondence, 1962-1966 (Box-folder 25:1)
  - Irving Howe- Correspondence with Robert N. Linscott, 1949, 1958 (Box-folder 25:2)
    Concerns his book The UAW and Walter Reuther (1949) and his complaint about his recent treatment at Random House (1958).
  - Joseph A. Johnston, etc.- Correspondence, 1958-1962 (Box-folder 25:3)
    Concerns a proposed biography of Johns Hopkins.
  - James Joyce- Articles concerning, 1951-1962 (Box-folder 25:4)
  - James Joyce- Ulysses- Correspondence, 1960-1963 (Box-folder 25:5)
    Concerning a new edition with Harry Levin and other scholars.
  - James Joyce- Ulysses- Correspondence, 1965-1973 (Box-folder 25:6)
  - James Joyce- Ulysses- Correspondence, 1932-1941 (Box-folder 25:7)
    Correspondence with Bennett Cerf (Copies) concerning the United States publication of the book.
  - James Joyce- Ulysses, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 25:8)
    Correspondence with Jack P. Dalton.
  - James Joyce- Ulysses, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 25:9)
    Editorial Explanations concerning the setting and pagination problems, with related articles.
  - James Joyce- Ulysses Illustrated, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 25:10)
    Correspondence and Photographs.
  - James Joyce- Ulysses Illustrated- Photographs, 1972, 8 oversize. (Oversize 25)
  - Philip J. Klass- Secret Sentries in Space- Correspondence, 1969-1971 September (Box-folder 25:11)
  - Philip J. Klass- Secret Sentries in Space- Correspondence, 1971 October-1973 (Box-folder 25:12)
  - Philip J. Klass- Secret Sentries in Space, 1971-1972, n.d. (Box-folder 25:13)
    Editorial Notes, Reviews, and Book Production Material.
  - Philip J. Klass- UFO's Explained- Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 26:1)
  - Philip J. Klass- UFO's Explained- Correspondence, 1975-1981 (Box-folder 26:2)
  - Philip J. Klass- UFO's Explained, 1973-1976, n.d., Editorial Notes, Reviews, and Book Production Material. (Box-folder 26:3)
  - Philip J. Klass- UFO's Identified- Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 26:4)
  - Philip J. Klass- UFO's Identified- Correspondence, 1968 January-July (Box-folder 26:5)
  - Philip J. Klass- UFO's Identified- Correspondence, 1968 August-1973, n.d. (Box-folder 26:6)
  - Philip J. Klass- UFO's Identified, 1967, Editorial Notes and Book Production Material. (Box-folder 26:7)
  - Philip J. Klass- UFO's Identified, 1968, n.d. (Box-folder 26:8)
    Editorial Notes and Book Production Material.
  - Philip J. Klass- UFO's Identified, 1966-1968 March, Reviews and News clippings. (Box-folder 27:1)
  - Philip J. Klass- UFO's Identified, 1968 April-1969, Reviews and News clippings. (Box-folder 27:2)
  - Rosanne Klass- Land of the High Flags- Correspondence, 1962-1966, 1969 (Box-folder 27:3)
    Including her perspective on Afghanistan as the first woman to teach provincial boys in Afghanistan (February 7, 1963); her visit to Kabul (August 16, 1965); copy of a letter from Howard Larsen, who was mentioned in her book (September 1, 1965); the effect of the India-Pakistan War on her research and her work while in Kabul (September 14, 1965, which is attached to September 29, 1965; September 29, 1965; October 4, 1965; November 12, 1965, December 18 and 28, 1965); and her discussion concerning Cormac McCarthy's book The Orchard Keeper (August 7, 1966).
  - Rosanne Klass- Land of the High Flags, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 27:4)
  - Rosanne Klass- Land of the High Flags, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 27:5)
    Editorial Notes and Book Production Material (undated) and Reviews (1964-1965).
  - Rosanne Klass- Three Great Moghul Women, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 27:6)
  - Pierre La Mure- Correspondence, 1955-1977 (Box-folder 27:7)
    Includes his boredom with his current lover and his preference for writing books as opposed to television and plays (August 18, 1955); his plan to write Clair de Lune about Debussy as his next book (October 7, 1955); his difficulty with his agent, Curtis Brown, over selling the movie rights to Beyond Desire and his attempts to interest various studios in the book (October 13, 1955; December 10 and 15, 1955); praise for the work of John O'Hara (December 20, 1955); reconciliation with his agent, Curtis Brown (January 30, 1956); the ending if his affair should be soon (April 6, 1956); editorial fact sheet for Clair de Lune (May 2, 1962); working on his book, The Private Life of Mona Lisa and request for reversion of rights to his previous books (March 18, 1972; April 3, 1974 and November 5, 1974); Random House not interested in The Private Life of Mona Lisa (December 2, 1974); and his death in December 1976 (December 8, 1977).
  - Pierre La Mure- Monsieur Toulouse A Play in Three Acts, n.d., Bound Typescript (Near Print). (Box-folder 27:8)
  - Malcolm Lowry- Correspondence, 1947-1967 (Box-folder 27:9)
    Includes a letter of gratitude for all the work by Erskine and Frank Taylor on Under the Volcano while at Reynal & Hitchcock and his return from his visit to New York (March 22, 1947); mention of Ultramarine and Lunar Caustic ([April 24, 1947] and May 3, 1947); snapshots of Margerie and Malcolm Lowry with an outline of his future work, "The book is three books: 1. Dark as the Grave Wherein my Friend is Laid. Which deals with our search for the original of Dr. Vigil to whom I was known as The Maker of Tragedies, and finding he had been murdered after drinking muchissimos mescalitos. 2. Eridanaus - a lyrical interlude, or intermezzo, taking place in Canada, and ending in a conflagration. 3. La Mordida, of which the book Under the Volcano itself is the villain, and ending in 'triumph,' so to say." (September 23, 1947); Erskine's criticism and concerns about La Mordida (March 21, 1952); snapshots of Lowry (August 15, 1953); reference to Lowry's hospitalization in a letter from Dave Markson (April 30, 1956); a letter from Margerie Lowry concerning his unfinished novel and her plans to finish it when she recovered from his death (July 14, 1957); and letters from Marie D. Moore of Harold Matson Company concerning the work of Margerie Lowry preparing Malcolm Lowry manuscripts for publication (November 15, 1957 through August 7, 1958)
  - Malcolm Lowry- Correspondence, 1946-1947, n.d., Copies. (Box-folder 27:10)
    Concerns the detailed discussion of the text of Under the Volcano in preparation for publication at Reynal & Hitchcock.
  - Malcolm Lowry- Correspondence with scholar, Gordon Bowker, concerning Lowry, 1988-1993 (Box-folder 27:11)
  - Malcolm Lowry- Correspondence of Erskine with scholar, Professor Sherrill E. Grace, concerning Lowry, 1989-1992 (Box-folder 28:1)
  - Malcolm Lowry- Lunar Caustic, 1952, Copies of correspondence and editorial notes of Mr. Giroux. (Box-folder 28:2)
  - Malcolm Lowry- Under the Volcano, 1947-1969, Copy. (Box-folder 28:3)
    Dust Jacket Designs, Reviews, and Author's Response to Editorial Notes by Erskine.
  - Cormac McCarthy- All the Pretty Horses, 1990, Typescript, Pages 1-127. (Box-folder 28:4)
  - Cormac McCarthy- All the Pretty Horses, 1990, Typescript, Pages 128-286. (Box-folder 28:5)
  - Cormac McCarthy- All the Pretty Horses, 1990, Typescript, Pages 287-396. (Box-folder 28:6)
  - Cormac McCarthy- Articles and Correspondence concerning McCarthy, 1982-1994, n.d. (Box-folder 28:7)
  - Cormac McCarthy- Blood Meridian- Correspondence, 1978, 1983-1986 (Box-folder 28:8)
    Chronicles his progress on the book.
  - Cormac McCarthy- Blood Meridian, 1984-1989, n.d. (Box-folder 28:9)
    Editorial Material and Reviews.
  - Cormac McCarthy- Child of God, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 29:1)
  - Cormac McCarthy- Correspondence, 1965-1992 (Box-folder 29:2)
    Includes problems with getting a visa for his English wife, Anne DeLisle (September 6, 1967); Erskine's work in getting sponsors for the Guggenheim application (October 1 and December 17, 1968); letters from Robie Macauley (May 27, 1971) and Gordon Lish (October 26, 1970, attached to February 25, 1971; another October 26, 1970; November 20, 1970); and letters from John Gallagher as the agent for McCarthy (December 14, 1971, March 1, 1972).
  - Cormac McCarthy- The Orchard Keeper, 1962-1964 June (Box-folder 29:3)